<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>ThanhLD Site</title>
        <link>https://ducthanh98.github.io/</link>
        <description>Hi, My name&#39;s Thanh 
 Skype: live:fushion48 
 PhoneNumber: &#43;84918279888</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 22:57:18 &#43;0700</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://ducthanh98.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>Az 104</title>
    <link>https://ducthanh98.github.io/posts/az-104/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 22:57:18 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://ducthanh98.github.io/posts/az-104/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Entra ID Users You must use Windows Server Active Directory to update the identity, contact info, or job info for users whose source of authority is Windows Server Active Directory. &ldquo;Bulk Create&rdquo; is for new Azure AD Users. Use &ldquo;Bulk invite users&rdquo; to prepare a comma-separated value (.csv) file with the user information and invitation preferences Use the New-AzureADMSInvitation cmdlet which is used to invite a new external user to your directory.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Golang</title>
    <link>https://ducthanh98.github.io/posts/golang/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 09:40:49 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://ducthanh98.github.io/posts/golang/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Garbage collection In Go (Golang), automatic memory management is handled by a garbage collector. The garbage collector is responsible for reclaiming memory that is no longer in use, preventing memory leaks and allowing developers to focus on writing code without explicit memory deallocation. Here are some key points about the garbage collector in Go: 1. Concurrency: Go&#39;s garbage collector is concurrent, meaning it runs concurrently with the application code. This concurrency helps in minimizing pauses and improving the overall performance of the application.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Microservice</title>
    <link>https://ducthanh98.github.io/posts/microservice/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 22:53:37 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://ducthanh98.github.io/posts/microservice/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Linux</title>
    <link>https://ducthanh98.github.io/posts/linux/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 22:53:02 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://ducthanh98.github.io/posts/linux/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Processes Concept A running instance of a program is called a process and it runs in its own memory space. Each time you execute a command, a new process starts. An active processs also includes the resources the program needs to run. These resources are are managed by the operating system(heap, process registers, program counters)
Each process has its own memory adress space and one process cannot corrupt the memory space of another process.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Algorithms</title>
    <link>https://ducthanh98.github.io/posts/algorithms/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 22:43:50 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://ducthanh98.github.io/posts/algorithms/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Bitmanipulation Binary AND &amp; 0 &amp; 0 = 0 0 &amp; 1 = 0 1 &amp; 0 = 0 1 &amp; 1 = 1 Example: 5 &amp; 7 =&gt; 0000101 &amp; 0000111 = 0000101 =&gt; 5 Binary OR | 0 | 0 = 0 0 | 1 = 1 1 | 0 = 1 1 | 1 = 1 Binary XOR ^ 0 ^ 0 = 0 0 ^ 1 = 1 1 ^ 0 = 1 1 ^ 1 = 0 Binary NOT ~ ~ 0 = 1 ~ 1 = 0 Binary LEFT SHIFT &laquo; a &lt;&lt; b =&gt; a * power(2,b) Binary RIGHT SHIFT &raquo; a &gt;&gt; b =&gt; a / power(2,b) Design pattern Creational patterns Factory Pattern: Factory Method is a creational design pattern that provides an interface for creating objects in a superclass, but allows subclasses to alter the type of objects that will be created which solves the problem of creating product objects without specifying their concrete classes.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Certified kubernetes administrator note</title>
    <link>https://ducthanh98.github.io/posts/cka/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 11:17:12 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://ducthanh98.github.io/posts/cka/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Architecture Overview Master Node: - Responsible for managing the K8s cluster, storing information about the nodes, containers, ... ETCD: - Database that stores informations in key-value format Scheduler - Identifies the right node to place a container based on the containers resource requirements, worker policies, constraints, ... - Controllers: - Types: - Node Controller: Responsible for onboarding new nodes to the cluster, handling situations where nodes are unavailable or get destroyed, - Replication Controller: ensures that the desired number of containers are running at all times in a replication group + - Workflows: - Monitoring status from the nodes and taking some actions to keep applications running.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Amazon Solution Architect Professional Note</title>
    <link>https://ducthanh98.github.io/posts/aws-sap/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 22:58:35 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://ducthanh98.github.io/posts/aws-sap/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[DDOS Type Application Layer: HTTP flood Protocol Attack: SYN Flood Volumetric: DNS Amplification Identify and Federation Policy Priorty Explicit DENY -&gt; SCP -&gt; Resource Policy -&gt; Permissions Boundaries -&gt; Session Policies -&gt; Identity Policies
Directory Service AD Connector: Only redirects no local identity data in AWS Simple AD: AD compatible managed on AWS AWS Managed MS AD: Establish trust connection with your on-premise AD Support AD Native schema extensions which required by some AD applications Large userS Integrates with radius/MFA IAM: Explicit DENY has precedence over ALOW NotAction: explicit allow a FEW THING in there Access Advisor: See permissions granted and when last accessed Access analyzer: Analyze resources that are shared with external entity Access Key: Can have two access keys Can be created, deleted, made inactivate or activate STS When you assume a role, you give up your permissions and take the permissions assigned to the role and vice versa Temporary credentials can&rsquo;t be cancelled Changing the trust policy has no impact on existing credentials Revoking the leaked credentials: Denying access to credentials created by AssumeRole, AssumeRoleWithSAML, or AssumeRoleWithWebIdentity Delete role, change permisisons impact all assumers you must have the PutRolePolicy to attach the AWSRevokeOlderSessions inline policy Denying access to credentials created by GetFederationToken or GetSessionToken edit or delete the policies that are attached to the IAM user Note: You cannot change the permissions for an AWS account root user so we recommend that you do not call GetFederationToken or GetSessionToken as a root user.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
